The next part I'm going to talk to you about is how to make a hat in Marvelous Designer.
Okay, if you have any questions during the process, you can also send me a message to ask me.
Okay, let's get started now, okay?
Okay, so the basics of making hats are that we have to draw a circle first.
This circle is a circle bigger than our head, because this is the hat behind us.
Okay, then I will use the positioning tool, which is the upper right corner, there is a tool like a small hammer, like a hammer heart.
I will position it on the head, and in order to review it, we will first switch to the black and white surface.
After switching, I will move this part of the hat and take a look.
Let it be centered with my head.
Okay, after it's done, because the 3D space has gravity, we will set the gravity to 0, so that our hat will not fall down.
After we have changed the physical properties, we can let the hat support it, and then we will adjust the gravity.
Next, I will use a fake sewing needle to fix it to the virtual model, and fix this plate to the head of the virtual model.
After I fix it, I can start to modify this hat.
Otherwise, it will look like this.
The level of the hat will still move.
Next, I will use the inner line tool to dig a hole for it.
This is the top of the hat we made later.
When you are making hats, you can make a hat very quickly in this way.
If you have any questions, you can send an e-mail to me.
Then I will drag the board to see the position and effect of this hole.
Just to see if the hole is too big or too small.
If the hole is too big, the hat will go through the top of the head.
If the hole is too small, the hat will not be able to wear it.
After that, we will dig this board down.
After that, we will make the side board.
Then it will form a hat.
Because we dug a board down now.
The fake sewing needle is in the position of the 3D window.
Take a look at the position of my mouse.
The fake sewing is here.
The use of the fake sewing tool is to fix the board to the virtual model.
OK.
Then we can continue to the back part.
Now I have a top board and a hat board.
I just need to sew the side board up.
Before that, I used the fake sewing to make the hat part.
The hat part is fixed on the virtual model's hair.
OK.
After that, I will measure the length of this circle.
Because the total length of the top board on the side of the hat should be the total length of this circle.
So we draw a rectangular board.
Then sew this board together with these two boards.
It will form a hat.
Then we use the line to sew.
In the process of sewing, press the Shift key.
You can sew between multiple sections.
After sewing, we add it to the side and start to simulate.
After starting to simulate.
Because now the overall effect looks soft.
Right?
So I will go to the attribute editor.
Increase the physical properties of the fabric, especially the bending strength.
Because the bending strength is controlled by the bending performance of your board.
If the bending strength is directly hardened, it is also possible.
Directly hardening is also possible.
But when hardening, your board is orange.
Sometimes it is not very clear to see the effect.
So I usually change the attribute of the fabric directly.
After increasing the bending strength, it will hold up.
We can look at the effect.
Here I have increased the bending strength.
After increasing the bending strength, does it hold up on the side?
After holding up.
Here we can see that this board is facing the back.
The gray part is outside.
So let's turn it over.
To ensure that its hair line is correct.
Then we sew the side.
After sewing, it forms the side of the hat.
Then we activate the top board.
Yes, after using this fabric.
It will look harder.
If you want a softer fabric.
Just use the default fabric.
Okay, so now we are.
This top is sewn.
Right?
After sewing with sewing thread.
It looks like a pot now.
Because the corner here is particularly round.
Then some of the magicians we want.
The first hat I made.
In fact, it is a magician and a dress hat.
The corner of the dress hat is definitely not so round.
Right?
Then we may have to make some adjustments later.
Here I use the editor.
Here I use the editor sewing line tool.
After choosing this sewing line.
On the right, we can set the folding angle.
By changing the folding angle.
We can make this board.
Its folding angle is more sharp.
Okay, here we adjust the number to 270.
Adjust to 270.
Then through this folding angle.
It can form a very sharp fold.
After forming a fold.
We can adjust the position of its seam allowance.
Because just now we have a seam allowance.
This hat can't be worn on the head very well.
Then we delete the seam allowance.
Adjust its position first.
So in the process of making a hat.
It is very necessary to adjust the folding angle of the sewing line.
Next, we will return the seam allowance.
Then when our seam allowance is set to the original seam allowance.
You will see this hat.
Once the seam allowance is applied.
Although its properties.
When we saw it just now.
Will feel that its properties are very hard.
But it is still the same now.
Can't hold it on the head very well.
So we will continue to optimize its fabric properties later.
Okay, then here.
We are going to put it.
Change its folding angle again.
Because the top folding angle has not been changed just now.
Set to 90.
After that.
It will stand up.
You see.
180 and 90 are very different.
Sometimes people may be thinking.
Why one is 270.
One is 90.
Do you know why this seam allowance is 90.
This seam allowance is 270.
They are also folding.
Why this side is 270.
This side is 90.
Let me see.
Are there any smart chats?
Yes.
Because we will.
Inward and outward.
It seems that everyone is very smart.
As for this side.
Because it is face to face.
This is a 90 degree squeeze.
It is a 90 degree squeeze outward.
This is an inward fold.
So it is 270 degrees.
Well.
Everyone is so smart.
Okay.
And then.
Because the fabric is relatively soft now.
We are here.
Also used.
Trim for grain leather.
It is the fabric of cowhide.
The feature of cowhide.
It has a very high bending strength.
Its bending strength is all 90.
The bending strength is all 90.
In this state.
We are going to simulate this board.
You will see that it is very hard to fold on both sides.
And it is a transform rate of 1.
So it is not easy to transform.
In this case.
We are going to use the folding angle.
It will be more sharp.
Just like the hat of the dress.
Yes.
So everyone is doing this.
Some of the harder fabrics.
When.
It can be used.
Trim for grain leather.
This fabric.
It is the cowhide fabric we often talk about.
Well.
Okay.
Then.
Sometimes.
If you want this.
Folding.
Side.
This.
Salt.
This is the version.
Called salt.
Then you want it to be softer.
Well.
For example.
It forms some waves.
Or.
Just.
Don't be so stiff.
Or.
If it is hard.
We can apply it to it.
For example.
This.
We can apply it to a new fabric.
And then turn it for inch increase.
Here.
The angle of an inchечение is down.
It's okay.
Yeah.
And then.
If you increase it.
The angle of an inch is increased.
Well, it's bigger.
A little harder.
That would you ask.
R.
When using other fabrics.
So.
Usually we can see that there are.
Three properties.
It's not the same.
Right.
But here.
I will give you these properties.
I'll adjust it later.
will be adjusted to a number why is it because we usually use the board is a rectangular board
or it is divided into horizontal and horizontal that this board it is not a round right round
board we go to use this rectangular is the production method, then it is not the same
because of the round board, it is at every angle of its fabric direction is irregular
it may be here is the value of the 45 degrees here is the level of this is because the software it set a dead direction is a direction
so we to ensure that it is in all directions of the properties are the same
we will put this round board we will put it these three values are unified
that is, for example, the bending strength is unified
gold tail sand right angle line tension ah are unified
well, this may sound a little bit gray and difficult to understand
but as long as you remember to unify them or say that the value is as close as possible
well, if you want to do the wave shape, then you just put the bending strength here to reduce
if you want to do very hard very hard, then you put the bending strength all to increase to 100
then you just put the bending strength all to increase to 100
well, just run everything like this
Next,
so we can take a look at the back,
as the surface Duplicometer pattern of our whole board is relatively Earth
that it must be on the cap on the head
that we will put the surface Duplicometer to reduce
the distance between the board and the body will be closer
then what we can start to simulate the state of motion
Or you can rotate the hat with the position ball in the state of not opening the model
This will make it faster to turn the hat
After the hat is put on the head, we can turn on the model and it will automatically wear
This is a harder hat
Why is it cut off?
This is the effect of our dress hat
Sometimes I want to see the next
There are some hats that have the effect of folding hats
The two sides may be rolled in
Like this
We can also use the function of fake sewing
Now we sew the two sides together
Fake sewing is the sewing between dots
After we create a fake sewing needle
The two sides will automatically roll up
Because it is equal to two dots sewn together
After that, we adjust the length of the line in the attribute editor
For example, here
I will adjust the length of the line
Set the length to 80
The distance between the two points is 80
Set to 60
It will roll up a little
The top of the model hat is particularly large
You can wait
Next we will have a step
Change the size of the hat
You can see if it is the effect you want
Because this is the video I recorded before
If you want this
If the inner roll is too round
Maybe you need to create more fake sewing needles
After creating these fake sewing needles
To control its length
We can let the side roll up
A lot of牛仔 hats
They will use this design
If you want to make a magician's hat
We usually make the top version a little bigger
If you write it down
Just to show you
How to make this hat
Like a magician
A little bigger on the top
A little smaller on the bottom
The effect
First of all
Because the hat of the magician is usually relatively high
We can increase the height of the side board a little more
This will make its top
A little higher
Then pull the top of this board
A little bigger
It will form the magician's own
Smaller below
Bigger on top
effect
but
Do you find this board
It's especially arched here
Do you know what the reason is?
It's arched here
MD
Can only use a piece of dough
To simulate the effect of hair
Can't do it directly
Because we are a fabric simulation software
I used to make hair
But the effect of the hair made
It's not a special pin
Because you are a piece of dough
Then now
Because of this
We just
Is it a physical attribute?
Is the curve intensity particularly high
When the curve intensity is relatively high
First of all
We now put this round board
Is the round board bigger?
After pulling
Is the size of this board
Is it longer than this side?
This board is relatively large
Then this side is relatively short
They all have a high curve intensity
Not easy to transform
So this circle
It's pulled up by this side below
Everyone can understand
So what we're going to do next
You see
Is it arched here?
Just because the top of this board
And the length of this side below
Can't match
It will arch
So are we going to
This side
Modify its length
To match this circle
Let's take a look at its length
Here
Use the length change tool
Change it to the same length as above
As long as you see
If you watch this live broadcast
You can also make your own hat
Because we will talk about a lot
Some details in making hats
Then
Did I use it here
After changing the length
The angle here is not right
It's two sharp corners here, right?
You see
Here is a sharp corner
If we now
Put two sharp corners together
It becomes a sharp corner
It's wrong
Because this hat looks from the back
It's bulging up
Right?
So next we're going to modify
These two
Just change this corner
And this corner
All modified to a straight corner
So we're going to use
Editing circle tool
Make a circle here
So is this a corner
Will be more like a straight corner
Adjust to circle
After adjusting to a circle
To simulate
It won't have the one just now
The problem of the sharp corner
So everyone
In the process of using MD
Be sure to pay attention
Especially like this side
At the end
This side and this side
When it will be sewn
This corner and this corner
Must be made into a straight corner
Even if it can't be made into a straight corner
Try to lean towards the straight corner
Understand?
After that
Let's adjust it
Adjust its position
Otherwise
Like just now
The hat is fixed
By this fake stitch
Its overall shape
It's not very good
So everyone is doing this
When the top and bottom
When it's small
Its side panel
It's actually a arch
You can understand
Because the arch
To ensure that
In the case of two straight corners
The length can also be right
So that's it
The method of the sofa pleats
In the previous episode
There is a home
That issue
Is talked about
Small partners can wait
After the live broadcast
Take a look at that issue
Then
We just adjust
The position of the fake stitch
It's almost
it is good
Next
Let's take a look
How to put
Such a hat
To be changed
The cover of a female
First of all
We first delete the fake stitch
Let this hat
Become a flat hat
Then freeze this hat
Let's modify the top panel first
First of all
We put this circle
Double click in the middle
Can activate the center point
So we can
Scrape the panel in the middle
Next
Let's shrink it
Into a smaller panel
Now
It's like a jar
Turned over
On the head
Right
Now
We are not
The top of this panel
Become a smaller panel
So
Is this edge
Is the length
Can't match
But we continue
To use the tool to change the length
Let this edge
The length
Can match
Here
Ok
We use the length
To change the root
Take a look
Its length
For example
Is 500
Here
We want to change the length
Become close to
Length
Ok
After the change
It's the same
Use the editor tool
Let it
Right
Then let this side
Also
The corner
Becomes 90 degrees
Ok
After I
After I adjust it
After that
Um
We found
This side
Ah
Um
The corner here
Is not close enough
To 90 degrees
We will add some
Um
This curve point
To manually adjust
Its curve
Let it
Both sides
As close as possible
To 90 degrees
Um
Our live broadcast time
Is not fixed
So
Ah
You can add
Our fans group
QQ group
Ah
This group is actually
Technical support group
Generally
If we have a live broadcast
Will be in the group
Announcement
Um
Then
Because now
Our top panel
Is relatively high
This is its excess part
Then
Re-create the sewing line
Ah
Pay attention to the direction of the sewing line
On the right
Then
Because the newly created sewing line
Is not
The fold angle used before
So
It naturally
Connected
Into a
Curve
Then
Next
We will adjust
The length of the two sides
Of the middle panel
Um
The purpose of clothes
Doing double layers
Is usually
Because
Doing double layers
You can first
For the inner layer
Use a fabric that is not easy to stretch
Then
For the outer layer
You can use a
Um
Bigger panel
Is
Through
The size of this panel
The difference
To
On the outer layer
Make a
Folding effect
Um
Good
Then
Next
We will adjust
Its side
Um
The curve line
And what else
The main thing to change
Is to make
These four corners
Are straight
As long as you can
Make sure
These four corners
Are straight
Its shape
Will not be particularly ugly
Why
Is it a curve now
The main reason
Is because
We
This panel
And the bottom
This circle
Its length
Is different
So we have to
Make a curve
Curve
We can change the pattern step by step
to make the pattern into a bow pattern.
This way, it becomes a women's sheepskin hat.
Now it's a Lufei's sheepskin hat, right?
Let's add a butterfly knot to it
to make it look cuter.
In the Library window,
in the Hardware and Trims folder,
there will be a butterfly knot.
If you can't find a butterfly knot,
click on the download button in the upper left corner
to download the butterfly knot file.
There are some here.
If there is no download,
you can download a copy separately.
Then double-click to import it to MD.
Then use this glue tool
to make the butterfly knot.
Just stick it on.
Now it's not a Lufei's sheepskin hat.
Because Lufei's sheepskin hat doesn't have a butterfly knot.
After that,
I will make a ribbon tie for it.
To make a ribbon tie,
you don't need to do anything else.
You can make a ribbon with the internal thread.
We will cut a ribbon out of it.
After cutting a ribbon out,
you can see the effect in 3D.
If the ribbon is too narrow,
we can redesign the value.
Then choose to cut and sew.
After cutting and sewing,
we select this plate
and adjust its thickness.
Here,
you must open the surface of the濃密紋理,
which is the shortcut key Alt 1.
Otherwise,
you can't see the thickness of the fabric.
This is why
I set the surface of the濃密紋理,
but I can't see its thickness.
Actually,
it's because
its thickness is not displayed.
Here,
we can choose a double-layer expression
to make it look like a double-layer fabric.
In this way,
through the thickness difference,
this plate looks like
a ribbon outside.
Then I can apply
a new surface
and change the color.
This is also a reminder
that this is with the butterfly.
After that,
we choose to sew the edge.
This is the circular version.
Use the border sewing line
to choose its circle sewing line.
Here, adjust the folding angle
a little bit.
In this way,
it will slowly fall down
and become the effect of covering the wool.
Use the positioning tool
to adjust the position of the butterfly knot.
So when making hats,
a very important point
is to use the border sewing line tool
to make some adjustments after choosing the sewing line.
Here,
we can set the strength of the sewing line
to 0 in the attribute editor.
After setting it to 0,
the hair line of the sewing line is gone.
It looks like a complete version.
In addition to the strength
of the 3D sewing line,
we can set the thickness of the sewing line
to 0.
If you change the thickness,
you can adjust the hardening effect
of the sewing line.
Here,
we set both the strength and thickness
to 0,
and then you can't see the seam line.
So you can pay attention
to the process you usually do.
Here,
we import a pre-made version.
After this version,
we set it to 50.
It's still a little big,
so set it to 30.
Next,
we are going to make a baseball cap.
The version of the baseball cap
is different from other versions.
It is a triangular version.
It has many triangular versions
to make a hat.
It may have six pieces.
Let's draw a triangle.
Next,
we will draw a polygon
along this shape.
In the process of drawing,
press the Ctrl key
to create a curve point.
The red dot
is the curve point.
After the creation is completed,
we put it
on the forehead
and look at its length.
Now,
we use the middle plate
and copy it here
to make a joint plate.
After the joint plate is made,
as long as we adjust
it,
the other plates
will also be adjusted at the same time.
Then,
here are the created joint plates.
We can put this useless plate
next to it
and turn it over.
Then,
use the line sewing tool
to sew it together on the side.
Something magical will happen
in a moment.
After sewing both sides,
let's put this plate on the side.
Then,
we turn it over
and make a ring.
Here,
I open the Alt2,
which is the texture surface.
We can see the front and back of the plate.
We must make sure
that the plates are facing the front.
This way,
we can find the direction
so that we don't make a mistake.
After arranging it,
we start the simulation.
We make it look like a pumpkin.
Then,
we switch its physical properties
to Trim for Green Leather.
Trim for Green Leather
is the leather material.
Then,
we start the simulation.
The leather material is hard.
It doesn't matter if it's not hard.
We just use hard material
to give it a shape.
Then,
we use Trim for Green Leather.
It's the same.
We can make the surface more sharp.
The particle diameter is 20,
so it has a little crack.
It's okay.
Next,
we sew the plate on the forehead.
After sewing,
you can see
that it's a little big
here.
Then,
we cut it off with the inner line.
After drawing with the inner line,
we use the edit tool
to select this line and cut it off.
We delete the excess part.
It's a hat.
Now,
the hat of the baseball cap is done.
It looks like a
moon.
Remember to add our
QQ group.
After the live stream,
I'll send the picture to the QQ group.
I'll make some hats.
You can try it.
Here,
I'll use the edit tool
to adjust the width
to make it look more flat.
Actually,
you can adjust the curve
little by little.
You can follow the effect of the 3D tool.
Okay.
You can drag this board
and adjust it a little bit.
Next,
we'll make the line effect of the sewing line.
First of all,
the simplest way is
to use the line tool.
Then,
click here.
It will automatically have the line effect of the sewing line.
In the attribute editor,
click the name
on the fabric window of our board.
You can switch to our line below.
After switching to the line,
here,
we can choose
whether to make the line of the fabric
or the line of the 3D.
Then,
we can choose offset.
In addition to
making a fake line effect,
we can also
make a frame
in the middle
to support the frame of the hat.
Of course,
if you can't see it,
it doesn't matter if you don't do it.
In fact,
it is very convenient to make this frame.
First of all,
you can choose a frame.
Use the tool of the edit board.
Choose a frame.
Then,
right-click on the inner line of the frame.
After the inner line of the frame,
enter the value of the frame here.
Here,
we can see
that the left and right sides are symmetrical.
Finally,
we will remove the symmetry.
After setting the value,
here,
we have
the finished board.
The other boards
have the same operation method.
First, draw the inner line.
After drawing the inner line,
we can make the frame
separately.
Okay.
Now we have finished drawing the inner line.
Right?
You can check its overall effect.
Okay.
After that,
we will start to make the frame.
In the middle of the hat,
there are some boards
to support the hat.
First of all,
we can use
the tool of the outline.
The tool of the outline
is used to
control the area of the frame.
For example,
if I want to control the edge of the frame,
I will select all the edges of the frame.
Or,
I can draw the inner line of the frame directly.
After drawing the inner line of the frame,
the inner line of the frame
will automatically
form a board.
Okay.
Let's laugh a little.
Then,
delete the excess part.
Because the frame
of the frame
will automatically stick to the inside
or the outside of the original frame.
If you are the inside of the frame,
it will stick to the inside.
If you are the outside of the frame,
you will stick to the outside.
Because the inner side of the frame
that we choose here
will stick to the inside.
After that,
we will re-create the sewing line.
This frame is completed.
Of course,
you only need to use the inner side of the frame.
Then,
this one frame
is completed.
The other frames
are also formed by using the same method.
Yes.
Then,
I want to see here.
I use the outer side of the frame
as the inner side of the frame.
Why do I use the outer side of the frame?
Sometimes,
some people don't want
the sewing line to be visible.
Some people
want the sewing line
to be invisible.
Then,
I will use the outer side of the frame
as the inner side of the frame.
Then,
I will delete
the inner side of the frame.
I will simulate it
to prevent the sewing line from being unstable.
Then,
I delete the remaining inner side of the frame.
After deleting the inner side of the frame,
I will start to simulate it.
From the outer side,
you can't see the sewing line
that is used for the frame.
You can only see the sewing line
between the frame and the frame.
Because you can only see the sewing line
between the frame and the frame,
do you remember that
you can only see the sewing line
between the frame and the frame?
Then,
I will select the sewing line
and delete
the 3D effect.
In this way,
it looks like a complete outer frame.
In fact,
whether you are making hats or clothes,
you can cut a layer of the outer frame
and delete the joint.
Then, delete the remaining inner line.
It looks like a whole version.
There is no inner line on the top,
but there is a line on the bottom.
In fact,
not only making hats,
but sometimes making boots
or bags
can be used.
OK.
Let me think about
what to do next.
Next,
I will show you
that there is no sewing line here.
Only the inner layer has a sewing line,
and the outer layer is invisible.
OK.
Then,
I will show you
how to make the border.
Before making the border,
we first
cut the inner line
of the button.
Then,
cut the two button plates
here.
Then,
the inner model
is re-activated by me.
Because
there is a loop
on the inner side,
it will be folded in.
Yes.
Sometimes,
the hidden model
may be visible.
Then,
re-activate the model.
Otherwise,
it may be unstable.
Let's make the hat first,
and then activate the model.
Then,
let's see
how long this side is.
For example, it is 21 cm.
Then,
the height is about 21-22 cm.
Of course,
you don't need to be so precise.
Just because I am used to it,
I like to be more precise.
So,
I will measure it.
Then,
choose the bottom side
and see how long it is.
Then,
create a rectangle.
Its width is the width we measured just now.
The height is the distance of the inner line just now.
22 cm.
Then,
let's move this model a little bit.
Of course,
in the process of using MD,
be careful not to overlap the panels in the 2D window.
Otherwise,
the UV you pour out will overlap.
Then,
there will be some problems.
the inner and outer layers are not penetrated.
Then,
in the process of sewing,
you must pay attention to this.
Because this side will be pasted
inside this panel later.
Right?
In MD,
if you cross the layers to sew,
it is very likely to be unstable.
In other words,
now this hat has two layers.
This is the outer layer.
This circle is on the inner layer.
If you put this circle
and the outer layer together,
it will keep shaking.
Because there is still a layer in the middle.
Then,
the sewing line will be identified.
There will be a certain identification problem.
It will be unstable.
In order to prevent such instability,
you must sew this side
on this layer
that is pasted together with it.
Do you understand?
Yes.
So,
if you cross the layers to sew,
it will be unstable.
You must pay attention to this point.
Then, sew it here.
In the process of sewing,
press the SHIFT key and do not release it
to perform multi-stage sewing.
After sewing,
select the right button of the panel
and add it to the side.
Or add it to the inside.
It will be pasted.
This circle is pasted.
After pasting,
I added it to the inside again.
Then, I remembered
that the side was not fixed.
So, I fixed the side again.
Then, I remembered
that I had forgotten to create the inner line.
So, I created it again.
Thank you for your praise.
In the process of using software,
it is not that
you just need to make a shape.
In fact,
there are many details.
In the future,
when you make other types of clothes,
you can pay attention to some problems.
Here, we set the folding angle to 0.
Otherwise,
it will be turned over.
Can you understand?
Then,
we activate the virtual model
and put on the hat again.
In the process of simulation,
once you see
the situation where the grid is turned over,
you must pause the simulation,
do not expect that
it will stabilize itself.
It cannot stabilize itself.
OK?
Look, if it is unstable,
you must drag it
until it is stable.
Then, we drag it patiently.
Do not drag it directly.
Drag it directly
because it is already
in a very unstable state.
If you drag it with external force,
it will be more unstable.
it will be unstable.
Oh, it's not that you are lagging.
I just moved the control Z back.
Then activate the other models
and drag the hat manually.
Because now
the whole effect I made
is more...
Is it lagging?
Is it still lagging now?
Hello?
Oh, OK, OK.
OK.
The hat I am making now
is a curvy edge.
Right? This hat.
My current angle is 270 degrees.
So sometimes
some men
may want
the hat to be
downward.
Can you tell me
if I want
the hat to be downward,
what should I change?
What should I change?
Is there anyone who can tell me?
The first answer is...
Oh, it's OK.
The first answer is
the curvy edge.
After the live stream,
chat with me in the QQ group.
I'll treat you to milk tea.
Curvy edge.
We need to change the curvy edge.
Looks like the baby is listening very seriously.
So let's adjust
the curvy edge
a little bit.
The hat will be downward.
OK.
Later, chat with me in the QQ group.
Curvy edge.
Curvy edge is me.
I'll treat you to milk tea later.
If you want to go upward,
adjust the value higher.
If you want to go downward,
adjust the value lower.
OK.
Then,
I'll make a curvy edge.
Uh...
I'm not driving.
I'm live streaming.
I can't live stream while driving.
After changing the curvy edge,
the curtain layer is OK.
The top point
can be replaced
with a button.
OK.
Then,
let's change the button type.
Because the top of the hat
has a
decorative top.
Here, we can change the type
to the half circle.
Or you can change it to a flat half circle.
Then, put it in a little bit.
It looks like the top point
of the hat.
OK.
Finally,
we come to the last hat type.
It's the artist hat.
It's also the painter's hat
that we often use.
The painter's hat is also the same.
We can copy and paste six of them.
Then, directly right-click and select the link pattern.
Then, it's the same.
Sew it together.
OK.
After sewing,
I stole a small basket here.
I remember that I directly frozen the middle pattern
and then let it open the simulation.
OK.
Then, I cut the pattern again.
Then, it became a melon hat.
When making this hat,
we usually make the most basic melon hat for it.
After making the melon hat,
put it in the 3D space.
Fix it.
Add a fixer.
Then,
if you want to make the painter's hat,
does the painter's hat have a characteristic?
It will first...
Let me see.
The painter's hat is like this.
It's closed in.
Right?
In other words,
you see,
this pattern has to be folded like this.
Right?
So,
if we want to change this pattern,
we have to make it fold first.
Like this.
Understand?
OK.
Next,
we add two straight lines on both sides.
Make sure the length of the left and right side
are the same.
Then,
put both sides out a little bit.
OK.
Because it's a joint pattern,
we change one pattern.
The next pattern will also be changed.
Then,
it becomes a painter's hat.
OK.
Then,
it becomes a pumpkin.
Like a little pumpkin.
This is the basis of our painter's hat.
Very simple, actually.
So, in the process of changing,
you have to try to understand
the structure of this pattern.
If it looks like
it's going to be bigger or wider
in this position,
then you can also
make it wider or bigger
in the corresponding position
of the corresponding 2D pattern.
Then,
here we also use the round corner tool
to make it a round corner on both sides.
This round corner is very hard.
This kind of hard round corner
is what we try to avoid
when we make clothes
or when we make projects.
Because it's quite troublesome
to modify it.
So, let's make it
a round corner first.
Can you understand it?
Thank you for your attention.
Thank you.
It doesn't matter if you don't understand it.
Later, we will upload
the full version.
I will talk about it again.
In that video,
you can take a look.
Okay.
Then, when making an artist's hat,
we have a basic logic.
That is,
we have to fix
the circle of the painter's hat first.
That is,
because
I have never worn a painter's hat.
Painter's hats are not like this.
Painter's hats are not like
baseball hats.
After you wear the baseball hat
on your head,
you shake your head,
it may not fall down.
But the painter's hat
is not very well fixed.
Yes, the painter's hat is an octagonal hat.
It is not very well fixed.
For example,
you shake your head and shake your head.
The hat falls down.
So, if you
put the baseball hat
on the person's head,
it is very difficult to fix it.
It will move.
So, we have to make a circle first.
Fix this circle on the model's head.
Then,
put the baseball hat on it
and sew it up.
It is not easy to shake.
Ah!
Yes, you can use a nail
to nail it on the head.
Let's make this circle first.
After that,
reduce the particle diameter.
These are the basic operations.
Then press Shift F to open
the
button.
Painter's hat is a baseball hat.
It is a bit like a baseball hat.
Then,
if its width is a little long,
let's make it wider.
Wait a minute.
Let me show you.
I remember the project file I opened at the end was a painter's hat.
This is the final result of the painter's hat.
There is a circle in the middle.
This circle is fixed on the model's head.
This is the painter's hat.
You can see it here.
It is a combination of six panels.
The final result is like this.
Then the final result.
This is the result of the final result.
Since there is a circle in the middle,
you also can make إنitial space
gamêr
The material is the SBSAR material that supports Substance after Marvelous Designer 10.
So you can directly import the SBSAR material into Marvelous Designer and open it.
In the end, the rendering of the finished product will be better.
You can preview this effect in MD first, and then render it.
Let's continue.
Then apply another material to this edge.
Adjust its width and put it on the head.
You see, I can't put it on like this.
If I can't put it on, I'll change it again.
Also use 8.
There is a version of 8.
Don't get old first.
It's best to use the new version.
I'll have a cup of coffee.
Then use the sewing needle.
It's the needle you're talking about.
Put it on the forehead here.
After that, we'll change its length.
Because if you don't fix it,
Because people's heads are all three-dimensional.
It's easy to move around.
Especially many models.
Its hair.
There are a lot of fine grid in the hair.
This kind of fine grid is easy to hook.
Let's put it this way.
You can understand it.
For example, it's your ears or hair.
There are a lot of boards and a lot of grid.
It's small.
Then I can also have a cup of coffee.
Yes, you can.
Then.
Oh, I forgot.
But I think milk tea is better.
The reason I drink coffee is just because I'm sleepy.
Oh, I can't remember what I'm going to say.
Then when your board has a larger particle diameter.
Its grid.
The top is also relatively wide.
There's a loop.
When the grid is relatively wide.
It's narrower than the tip of the hair.
Right?
It's going to be wide.
Just his.
Just imagine it.
His grid is relatively large.
Then this grid is relatively small.
Then the grid is large.
The top.
It's easy to be blocked by the small top of the grid.
Block.
This will lead to.
Sometimes you will find.
When I was making hats or doing some scarf.
I don't know why he was hooked by what eyelashes and ears.
This is because the particle diameter of your board is too large.
Because when we created the board.
His default particle diameter is 20.
Right?
When the default particle diameter is 20.
This grid is small.
He hooked it up.
When you encounter this situation.
Sometimes you can't drag it out by hand.
Then you use this tool.
This is a selection grid tool.
Pick it up.
Then pull it out.
Just pull it out with the positioning ball.
Or pull it out with a fixed needle.
Don't drag it out by hand.
Sometimes drag it out.
If you drag it out too much.
It may be hooked up by other places.
Then here we increase the friction coefficient.
When we increase the friction coefficient of a fabric.
It's not easy to slide.
It will be fixed on the top of the head.
Because sometimes people do waistband.
There are some belt.
And also when making hats.
You may find.
And when making socks.
You will find.
Why is this board always sliding?
He's been moving.
He will move to his waist.
Or he will move to your ankle.
In fact, the main reason is.
Because your board is too large.
The board is too narrow.
Just like people wearing clothes.
Yes.
If silk socks.
Not silk shoes.
Silk socks.
Just.
Because sometimes.
In the process of you doing it.
Your board may actually be made very small.
Much smaller than the human body.
But because Marvelous Designer.
There is no concept of damage.
He will.
The board will go to itself.
This.
And the narrow place to slide.
Just like you wear clothes.
If.
If you wear a T-shirt.
Well.
He will be stuck in the neck here.
Can't get down.
Just.
If his size is a little small.
You can't get down.
Ah.
It's the same for making skirts and clothes.
He will go to the thinnest waist himself.
And.
Yes.
Not fit.
It will go to the knee.
So.
When you encounter this situation.
It's best to go first.
Change the width.
Change a little bigger.
Yes.
Then.
Because I just used this.
The bending strength is 90, 90, 90.
That is, this bending strength is relatively high.
Then.
You see.
He will arch here.
There will be a non-adjustable gap here.
Is it right?
Because you are in other places.
We are all fixed with a sewing needle.
Then these two sides.
His bending strength is high.
He's like a.
The arch shape.
Hey.
Then we will reduce the bending strength a little bit.
He will be more attached to your head.
If you are not attached to the big size.
There are many ways.
For example.
Increase.
Or.
Well.
Just change it a little bit.
Yes.
Adjust it.
Give him a drag.
In fact.
What you do here is very simple.
What you have to do is.
Put that first.
Basic.
This one.
The board is done.
Wait a minute.
We're going to sew the hat on this little board.
That's it.
Now it's like making a headband.
Here.
It's also a change of color for him.
Remind yourself.
Oh.
This board is here.
Well.
That.
Now.
There are some grid breaks.
It doesn't matter.
The main problem with this grid break.
It's because.
Well.
We just.
Yay.
Yes.
We just made a bad point.
Now I have to add a sidebar for it.
Yeah, there's an important thing.
Reverse high gradually.
Let me into that unit for now.
I can offer you an example, right?
Yeah.
There's a lot.
All right.
Let me bring it to the side.
Um.
If you just wanted to change the part.
What you're going to do is.
Uh.
That you want it.
We have to go from another side.
Emergency.
We all need to get them all from one side.
You see?
Yeah.
Let's see.
No, you said all right.
Let's see, there's a three- subway bridge.
Ciao.
Wushuang.
Oh.
You can see that the particle diameter here has dropped to 5, which is normal.
And then because this board is relatively small, so it doesn't matter.
Sometimes people will say, oh, why is it so lagging in the process of using MD?
Many times it is because you have lowered the size of the large board to 5 during the adjustment process.
Then your network gap will be a lot, of course it will be lagging.
So all you have to do is take a look at the small board, you can use a relatively small particle diameter all the time.
If it's a large board, you can give it a little time to reduce the effect and then go back.
After this side is done, we will freeze it and we will not move it again.
Then, without opening the model, put this melon skin on the head.
Here we are using a line sewing machine to sew it on one side and then on the other side.
Uh, uh, it's me.
Hello, peach flower shop, it's me.
It's an octagon hat, right, right, right.
I just call it melon skin.
That's because the default fabric we just used is leather.
The leather fabric is very hard, right?
Then we change it to wool here.
It's wool, so it doesn't look that hard.
At the same time, it can keep a little thickness.
If you don't know how to use each fabric,
Uh, we had a video before.
Ah, there is an Excel table in the video.
There is a corresponding one on the Excel table.
That's where this fabric is used.
Then you can just look at that one.
Then here you can reduce the particle diameter, reduce the thickness, and adjust it.
Hey, you see, but when I adjust it, you just drag it off by hand.
Let it collapse.
Then pull it out and pull it out again.
Pull out a more beautiful shape.
Yes, there is a pattern, there is a pattern.
Uh, our software and Claw are actually the software of the same company.
Yes, I only make hats today.
Uh, and then wait a minute.
And then what about Claw?
It's for, uh, fashion designers.
It can be imported and exported.
In fact, it is connected to production.
Marvelous Designer is for some games.
Ah, for visual effects.
The company uses it.
We can't import and export 2D versions.
But, uh, we will have some for the CG industry.
For example, such as top.
And, um, there are carvings.
Carving brush.
These tools.
Um, we are not the same for the user group.
Ah.
Then what about me here?
Just pull this board a little longer.
Just a little longer here.
So that by dragging.
I can make this board look a bit like a chef's hat.
Um.
Then drag it again.
Ah.
But you can find that it is actually just a difference in height.
It won't make the width of the whole board different.
So you can change it back a little bit.
And then it's also.
Ah.
Drag it while simulating.
Let it form a better shape.
Then, uh, we can also pull the board a little wider.
Hey.
Let him, um, have more fabric.
Because the board was relatively narrow just now.
I found that it didn't have the kind of volume during the dragging process.
Let me do some for him.
For example, the effect of the hat leaning to one side.
So I'm going to make the board a little wider.
Yeah.
It's like leaning to one side.
It's more like.
It's like seeing those hats in real life.
All written and worn.
That's what you're wearing.
It's especially correct.
Looks unconventional.
Then I'm studding it into direction.
Then adjust it.
Because our board.
This board of this to side board is more in would with the head size.
This board.
Is this board.
More zoom-in.
Here's where there'll be some small frills.
And when it's done.
As you can see.
Theところ.
Deleting quick little frills.
I didn't go too far.
up along this side of the deck.
After that, I will select this edge and add a flexible line to it.
The detective hat is also done in this way.
It is also put together in six pieces like this.
Then after drawing a flexible line, it will produce some wrinkles along this edge.
Let's draw this ratio a little smaller, 95%.
Then adjust the ratio to 5 and simulate it.
There will be some wrinkled wrinkles here.
Then drag it manually.
Many times I don't even realize that I'm dragging it.
It's just some regular operations.
It's just a habit to drag and pull some wrinkles out.
OK.
Oh, it really looks like a waiter's hat.
Then finally add a button to it.
That's about it.
Let me see what's behind.
Behind is the flexible edge.
Finally, I thought about whether I should keep this edge.
Some hats have this edge outside.
Some hats have this edge inside.
Then I finally used a leather fabric for it.
I thought there was a weird edge on the leather fabric.
So I finally turned this edge inside out.
Then it's the same.
Here, use the fold angle tool to pull it back to zero.
Then simulate it and turn it inside out.
Then print it and make it a little thicker.
Then I remembered it.
I felt that this point couldn't be turned inside out.
It's so weird.
Then I didn't react to it at that time.
I said, oh, oh, oh, is there any problem with this version?
Finally, it's because my fake hairband didn't delete it.
Then I think about it.
Oh, it turns out to be like this.
I forgot to delete the fake hairband.
Then simulate it again.
It's put back.
Let's activate the virtual model.
Finally, this hat is done.
The overall angle is zero.
It's like this.
Well, that's all about the hat.
Let me show you what the concept of the vertical angle is.
Yes, it takes about ten minutes for me to make a hat.
But you don't have to show your boss this.
This video.
Let's use another color to see it.
Change to a clear color.
There is an inner line here.
Then this is the front.
Then the black part is the back.
This can be understood.
Then let's use this side.
Vertical angle.
This vertical angle and the vertical angle of the hairline line are the same.
Well, there will be a recording of the part of the old man's live broadcast.
But what he said today is relatively simple.
A little more comprehensive.
Because the old man also suddenly had some things.
Then you see.
This is the back.
This is the front.
From the front to the top.
Which is 0.
Is 0.
Then If you tilt it inward, it will be 360.
Donglaba.
360.
It means to say.
For example, I am here.
Oh, it will be 360.
Oh it is 0.
When you set to 0.
These two.
This plate is folded.
Donglaba.
It is actually equivalent to the angle from one side of this side to the other side
When it is folded in the opposite direction, it is 0 degrees
When it is 360 degrees, it is folded like this
Fold inward like this
Hmm
OK
Thank you, thank you
Do you have any questions about using Marvelous Designer?
Let me see what time it is now
Wow, it's 8 o'clock now
Choose the edge and then change
Yes, changing the elasticity can do some of these effects
Here are some uneven effects
You see, for example, like this
I didn't give it elasticity
It looks more even
Then I shrunk the elasticity here
It looks like there are some wrinkles that look like traces
In fact, the main reason is because in real life
Our board
In the process of sewing
The strength of the sewing line is uneven
So it will have such an effect
It looks more real
How to add the edge
Just choose one edge
Then create one
This board
Then the sewing line is sewn up
Or you just choose one edge
Then the inner line is stiff
Draw a board
Let's draw a board
Choose a board
Then the bottom right
The inner line is stiff
Offset as internal line
Its Chinese is the inner line stiff
Then cut and sew
Cut and sew
Freeze
Let it freeze
Then now we are on the texture surface
Can't see the thickness
To be replaced with a thick texture surface
Wait a minute, let me show you a Chinese one
This is Chinese
Wait a minute
The inner line is stiff
Then freeze
Ouch
Cut the sewing line
Activate
Then through its
The difference in the thickness of the diffusion
For example, the thickness of our hemispheres is different, then it looks like a hemispher, it will be thicker here, and it will be thinner here, understand?
This method is more convenient and intuitive.
If you have any questions, why don't you add our QQ group?
I also do the headband. I actually think the headband is okay.
The basic method of the headband is like this. Let me give you a simple demonstration.
Wait a minute. First of all, the headband is like this. We first need to have a rectangular plate, right?
This is a plate, we use a new fabric for it.
And then, because the headband has a lot of wrinkles,
after folding these, we can first select these lines and right-click.
Click on the line inside the curve line to add a few more.
After adding a few more, use the flip-folding tool to fold it.
When folding, select the headband.
Don't ask me why it's the headband, I don't know either.
Anyway, I think the effect of the headband is better.
Then select three roots, then confirm, then print.
Fold it for him.
Okay.
After folding, does this plate form like this?
Sometimes it's protruding outward, sometimes it's bulging inward.
Then I'll unseal it.
After unsealing it, fix it with a fixer on both sides.
Double-click here.
Why don't you add it to me? Double-click.
Then double-click here.
After double-clicking, it looks like noodles now.
Then there is a fixer on both sides, right?
After two sides have a fixer, turn the fixer like this.
Ah, it turns too fast.
Okay, after turning here, let's get closer.
It's not stable, so you have to turn it slowly.
I'm lazy here, so I'll turn a little faster.
Okay, turn it.
Turn it.
Well, after turning it, put this end near the head.
Okay.
After the head is near, fix the fixer to the head of the virtual model.
I'm just showing it roughly here.
And then, yeah.
And then, turn it like this.
Just wrap it up like this
In the process of winding
Just use this fake seam
The fake seam is on the model's head
The fake seam is fixed to the model
Fix it like this
simulation
it is good
Then just give it a round
Just wrap it up like this
it is good
It's the same in the process of winding
Use this fake seam
Give it a fake seam to the virtual model
Fix it to the virtual model
Fix it up
Then it's the same
Anyway, the process is that you have to do it through this fixed needle
Understand
Just drag this fixed needle
In the case of no movement
Continue to give it
Just wrap it up
If he is more disobedient
You just pause here
Then use the fixed needle to fix it on the virtual model
Give him a fix
Fix it up
The next step is to repeat the operation
Then roll it up
Take a look at its direction
Roll it here like this
Turn
Turn this fixed needle
Zoramia
It's a bit like Zoramia
If the GPU simulation is not stable
You can put this
Wait a minute
GPU quick simulation
There is a simulation property here
There is an intersection solution at the bottom
Hook it up
Intersection solution hook up
It will be better if you hook it up
And then this kind of self-converting detection
This can also be hooked up
Will be better
Just what happened
Oh
I just remembered that I just switched to quick simulation
Just changed to GPU simulation
Scared me
I said what happened
GPU simulation is like this
Just no CPU simulation
The simulation effect is good
Indian women's head
I think it's okay
That's a big piece
I don't think there is such a male
Male head is difficult to wrap
In fact, the male head
You just continue to do this
Just give him a little bit of it
Just do it
Roll it up
After that
Just reduce this particle diameter
I just went around one layer
You're in the process of doing it
It must be a lot of layers
I didn't put it up here
In general, let him continue to roll
After rolling it up
Just sew it up
Just sew it up a little bit at the end
It's okay
Cover the head and neck
Just show a face
That kind of
That kind of you just use a large piece
Just use a fixed needle to roll it up
That's more convenient than this
Just this
I'm still rolling it up for him
If you pay for the course
Mid-April
Pushing out
may
Let me see what time it is
Let's get to nine o'clock
That's about the end of today's question
What other questions do you have?
I'm going to fall down
Pull it up
Now it's kind of like a wooden milk
The fixed needle is not the new function of 11
The fixed needle is from our software
Just already have the function
There are fixed needles in every version
The fixed needle is here
This is the fixed needle
The red needle is the fixed needle
This is called a fake needle
It's a nail
It's a dot to a dot
It's okay to rotate the virtual model
It's just that the method is what everyone thinks of
Right?
You think that method is better
That method is okay
Because I haven't tried to rotate the virtual model
I can try it next time when I have time
I'll try next time
Are there any other questions?
You can add our Q group
Choose the flexibility of the bias change
Do you mean the flexibility here?
Can also
can also
If you still have any questions, yes, yes, let me find it for you, you're talking about this, right?
This, this edge, yes, the fold here is made of elastic, this edge is made of elastic 95.
Then the fold here is not, the fold here is because, because this edge is shorter than these long edges added together.
You see, you can see it with the editor's sewing machine.
Here is 111, here is 131.
The length is different, so it has some, it has some folds.
You can understand, right?
Because there are many panels here, there are few panels here.
Sorry.
OK, OK.
If you have any other questions,
you can go to our, what happened here?
If you have any other questions, you can go to our QQ group to ask.
When we have some other courses coming out later, you can also pay attention to it.
And you can also click to pay attention to our live broadcast room, OK?
Well, that's all for today.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you for watching for so long.
Thank you.
Thank you for your support of our software for so long.
We will also release more teaching videos in the future.
And then today's hat practice, if you have any other places you want to know,
you can wait for the follow-up version of our print version to come out, which is the teaching video version.
Well, that's it for today.
Bye bye, everyone.
OK, bye bye to everyone andtight.
Bye bye.
Thank you, everyone.
Mm compliance.
Bye-bye, everyone, bye.
Thank you for your support.
Bye bye.
All right.
I'll stop here today.
Bye bye.
Thank you.